Whew!
It's getting real hot out here.
I'll do one more song and call it a day.
What?
I want AKP48!
The crowd's clearly gotten
bigger after sports day.
There's a real chance that she'll beat
yours truly in terms of popularity.
That said,
Ever since I met you
she's no closer to putting on
a street performance.
Is she actually writing any songs?
My heart's been pounding
Hmm?
And it just won't stop
Who's that girl?
It's kind of bothering me
Good mornings, bye-byes...
What's wrong?
Forgot her lyrics?
Probably broke a guitar string.
Sorry, that's all for today.
See you next time.
Aww...
Pardon me.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Hello? Can you not hear me?
Hey!
I'm Yamabuki, and you?
Okay, okay, I'm sorry for
ignoring you! So don't do it!
I'm glad you can see me.
I was afraid I'd died and become a ghost.
Why did you ignore me?
Because you seemed annoying.
Rest assured, for I am anything but.
In fact, allow me to list ten reasons why.
S-So you are annoying!
I just wanted to ask you why
you seemed so put off back there.
Is there something you didn't like
about Inohana's show?
Well, what do you think?
About her show, I mean.
I think she's doing pretty well.
She has her finger on the pulse
of what songs are popular,
and she's good at copying
the originals' singing styles.
But... she does seem
to get self-conscious.
You know what that means?
It's the songs that are popular, not her.
Anybody else could cover them.
She wasn't like this before...
Are you a friend of hers?
Happy now?
Not really.
Let me ask you a couple more questions.
How are you so fast? That's freaky!
KARAOKE
I need to work on my original songs.
LYRICS 1 FOR CONCERTS - NEW SONGS - LYRICS 2 FOR CONCERTS
NEW SONGS
KARAOKE HOUSE
SCORING MODE EX
LOADING!
Maybe I should actually tell Yamabuki-kun
that this might be too hard for me.
I've brought your melon soda.
Huh? I didn't order that, though?
What, you don't want it?
In that case, I'll help myself.
How did you know I'd be here?
Your old friend told me.
I actually know her, too.
You know Aiko?!
Oh, so her name is Aiko?
She was quite the handful.
She wouldn't even give me her name.
I took his bait...
She looked really bored
as she watched your show,
so I had a little chat with her.
What did she say?
Your expression tells me
you already have a good idea.
Yeah...
Aiko hates me for only doing
covers of popular songs.
Because she loved the songs I wrote.
Then just perform
original songs at your shows.
Don't wanna.
Why not...
I'm not telling you.
It's something I'm embarrassed about.
But that's a problem.
I have a duty to turn you into a pro.
What must I do to get you to tell me?
This is a karaoke room.
You gotta sing.
Karaoke battle.
SCORING MODE EX
I'll tell you if you do better than me.
Singing battle versus an aspiring singer?
You really don't intend to tell me!
I accept your challenge, however.
I'll go first, then.
Wait, wait.
I demand a handicap.
You'll sing a song that I pick.
It's one you sang in your show yesterday.
No objections there, right?
Yeah, that's fine by me.
However, you also have to do the dance.
Wha?
LOVE YOU!!
What? Why?
Like I said, it's a handicap.
Go on. It's about to start.
Huh? Wait, what?
Ever since I met you
My heart's been pounding
And it just won't stop
Victory is mine.
I thought so during your show, too.
You get self-conscious and give off that
"I only do this because I have to" vibe,
hoping we'll read through your lines.
That defensive behavior must
be what angered your friend...
Ever since I met you
My heart's been pounding
And it just won't stop
It's kind of bothering me
Good mornings, bye-byes,
And even the mundane nights
Make me think of you
I wanna say
"You've grown a little taller"
"We use the same notebook"
"Thank you for the other day" and more
But I still can't bring myself to
Whenever I hear your voice,
my vision gets all sparkly
I can't seem to get you off my mind
There's something
I wanna tell you eye-to-eye
Th-This girl!
She's way fiercer than I thought!
It's how I feel
I'm in love with you
Y-You...
S-So how exactly am
I self-conscious, again?
I've brought your hot tea with honey.
I'm so sorry for interrupting!
IT'S HOT, SO PLEASE BE CAREFUL
SCORE: 95.925 / NATIONAL AVERAGE: 84.836
ANALYSIS: YOU'RE AN AMAZING SINGER.
Yeah, that should do it.
Wh-What?
That's trouble.
It's do or die.
I'll bet it all on this song!
I hope you have your medicine ready.
Yours truly has a beautiful voice.
It might intoxicate you, so watch out.
A BUS WON'T TAKE US TO THE MOON
I'm not a special person
I'm well aware of that
I thought so when we did
that show together in the spring,
That's why, whenever we talk
and it's the same now.
He's not that good at singing.
I give you the cold shoulder
But... This song...
SCORE: 75.129 / NATIONAL AVERAGE: 82.172
ANALYSIS: YOUR VIBRATO SOUNDS LIKE A DOG WITH A CRUSHED THROAT, BRO.
The machine has to be malfunctioning!
This score's unacceptable for a Yamabuki!
A 20-point gap, huh?
W-Wait! 20 points is
basically the margin of error!
Why did you sing that song?
Hey, can I ask you one last thing?
What?
The band logo on your shirt.
Do you like that band?
Oh, this? Yeah, I like 'em.
It's the band Rikka loved.
Listen, Arisu!
I found this amazing band!
They're not that well-known,
but they're called...
Hugg Notes? I loved them.
A certain someone recommended them to me.
Fine.
I'll tell you why
I don't sing original songs.
Are you sure? I lost!
I said whoever does better wins.
The scores don't matter.
Your song was better.
Yes!
Man, you really hate losing.
Stuff happened in my past,
and now I can't sing my
original songs in front of people.
Elaborate.
I'm scared.
Of the looks people give me when
they judge me or think I'm a letdown.
Covers are much easier because I can
hide behind other people's music.
How cowardly, right?
I see. She's scared of the
audience's judgmental eyes?
A straightforward trauma,
and a critical one.
If it's not resolved at once,
she has no future.
I've been trying to write a new song,
but remembering those eyes
stops me dead in my tracks.
It's affecting her songwriting, too.
What should I do?
Right. We'll just have to
do this the Yamabuki way.
You're scared of having eyes on you?
I used to be that way, too.
You know that's my tea, right?
I had to take part in numerous
extracurricular activities.
Presentations and speeches
were part of that.
The piercing gaze of the audience
is something I know all too well.
How did you get over your fear?
Even if you can't write a new song,
you still have your old ones, right?
Huh? I guess?
Then it's clear what we must do.
We'll do an "Inohana Rikka
Original Songs School Concert."
Wha?
You just have to get used to it.
Experience is everything.
I'll arrange a venue
and an audience.
Don't decide for me!
It doesn't have to be a new song,
but you can only perform your own songs.
Don't you think you're being
a bit insensitive?
This is normal for the Yamabuki family.
Even you should be able to do it.
Okay, fine.
Excellent. Now, as for when...
We'll do the concert a week from now!
The school rooftop?
Why not my usual spot?
I thought you'd understand how I feel,
but I guess I was wrong.
In the end, you're not mediocre like me.
Are you the same as that guy?
I thought you'd be up for it.
Maybe I expected too much of you.
Sorry, Yamabuki-kun.
I really don't think I can...
Hey, you're finally here.
Rooftop scary!
We get to hear your original song
after so long, Rikka-chan!
Yay!
Huh? Why are you all here?
Where are the other spectators?
It's just the four of us.
Did you really think
I'd throw you to the wolves?
In order to get used to
the audience's gaze,
you start with friends and family.
You should've just told us
if we could help you overcome it.
We'll watch you
with the clearest of eyes.
We get VIP seats! That's so cool!
Relax. I've locked the door.
You have nothing but allies here.
Shake your fear and sing for us.
FURIN HIGH SCHOOL
Oh, uh...
It's been ages since I last played
my songs for you, huh?
Well, damn...
I don't even know what to say.
Did I wrongly assume that she'd be
able to do it in front of friends?
It seems her trauma is quite
deep-rooted. What do I do now?
Sorry...
Rikka!
Rikka-chan!
RIKKA FTW - WE STAN INOHANA
You always put up a front
and never tell us anything.
You should at least vent to us sometimes.
RIKKA
We kinda made these sloppy last-minute,
but we'll do better when it's for reals.
RIKKA LOVE
Imagine we're always in the front row.
Just look at us when it gets tough, okay?
Yeah, okay.
You're going to be a singer, Rikka-chan?
Will you take the stage
at the Tokyo Dome someday?
I wanna see you sing in a huge venue.
As we looked up the open blue sky
Pull some strings
and get us front-row seats.
In bright white letters
That'd be great!
Close enough to see your face!
We wrote about our purpose,
we wrote about our future
Right... I'd made a promise.
And painted it with your dreams
That I'd get them front-row
seats to my concert.
With each passing "See you tomorrow"
Our hearts grew closer
I can't believe you tricked me.
Way to destroy my trust in you.
S-Sorry. I figured you wouldn't be
nervous if I told you in advance.
Apology rejected.
How can I redeem myself?
Treat me to karaoke and help me practice.
If that'll repair your trust, sure.
One time probably isn't enough, though.
Did my credit score go down that much?!
Wh-What's it at right now?
If it was at 100 before,
it's around 80 now.
It fell 20 points!
20 POINTS IS BASICALLY THE MARGIN OF ERROR
In the middle of outer space
We seize our very own reason
that we can only find here
It starts running and running
That song, which she probably
wrote a long time ago,
Becoming a nameless warmth in our hearts
was rough around the edges
but very Inohana.
And our world
And it definitely touched hearts,
even if crying was a bit over the top.
I have no idea why she locked
that talent away,
but she's taken a step forward
thanks to her clubmates.
I thought I could guide them myself,
but that was hubris on yours truly's part.
When they run into adversity one day,
it probably won't be me
who helps them overcome it,
but rather the bonds between them.
With that in mind,
why don't you four hang out and have
fun together to bolster your solidarity?
Why the shopping mall?
My little sister loves this place.
Do you want to buy something here?
I want to get sneakers
for my little sister.
Why'd you pick somewhere so far away?
This place has good parfaits,
or so my little sister said.
Sis this, Sis that! Come with her, then!
We haven't been hanging out
a lot lately, huh?
Prepping for sports day
kept us all busy.
I want to get some new clothes!
Feel free to have fun however.
Pay no mind to yours errand boy truly.
I don't care about you by default.
Hey, wait!
I told you to have some fun together.
Hey, Mr. Errand Boy.
If you're free, help me pick out clothes?
I don't mind, but wouldn't it be better
to ask the girls instead?
Well, actually,
I've put on weight lately.
I don't want them to know.
But it's okay if I know?
Yamabuki-kun.
Let's get going.
What do you think of this?
How about this?
Is this a bit too showy?
Balanced, but less isn't always more.
Seventy-eight points.
I didn't expect you to
try this hard to help me.
Anyway,
you've only tried on white clothes.
Because I like white.
I'm wearing a white outfit right now.
I like white, you see.
Come to think of it,
Apollo said something similar.
I keep seeing traces of Apollo
in these girls every now and then,
but I still lack conclusive proof.
A lot of people like the color white...
So, tell me.
Does your silence mean
that you like this showy outfit?
As if!
Yeah, it's the best one so far.
You look very cute.
Cu...
I-I didn't ask you to go into
that much detail...
Wait, where did the other three go?
Bucky! Help!
It's an emergency!
Come with me right now!
It's stuck in the chute!
After I spent 1,000 yen, too!
And you want me to get it out?
Please. I want it bad.
Yours truly is adept with crane games.
Just you watch.
The claw is set to have
a weak grip strength.
So instead of using it to grab,
you use it for pushing.
Stop! The stuffing's gonna come out!
Yours truly is also adept at sewing.
I want it undamaged!
That's yours truly for you!
Here.
What are you doing?
Putting my scent on it.
I don't want it to smell unfamiliar.
When I was little,
I couldn't sleep without a plushie
that had my scent on it.
Now she's sounding like her, too.
Hey, is that habit—
Oh, you can go now, Bucky.
Thanks for the help.
Ugh!
They're all just doing their own thing!
There's no point if they
don't hang out together!
Hey, errand boy!
Want some takoyaki? I ordered too much.
I've told you not to call me
an errand boy loudly in public.
What's the problem?
If I don't call you that, then...
Then what?
Then nothing. Come on, eat up.
Mentai mayo is the best way
to eat takoyaki.
I always order that flavor.
Let me ask you one thing.
What flavor did you get?
Huh? Salt and green onions, why?
Oh, okay.
I got mentai mayo, too.
You did?!
What's gotten into you?
Do you like mentai mayo that much?
Let's eat.
Sorry, can I get a toothpick?
Here.
Say aah.
Why are you feeding me?
What else am I supposed to do?
We only have this one toothpick.
Well? Does it feel good?
"Feel good"?
You mean "taste good."
It must feel good
to be fed by a ten like me.
A-Anyway, do you know where Inohana is?
Says she's watching ducks by the river.
Why'd she leave the mall?!
I'll go drag her back!
Thank you for the takoyaki!
You could've acted
a bit more flustered, y'know.
What was even the point
of teasing you, then?
I said to have fun together,
but since you refuse to do as I say,
I say we need a change of plans.
We're doing karaoke instead!
So loud!
The lighting's so lewd.
This place has great honey tea.
Now you'll have no choice
but to deepen your bonds.
They've always been deep.
Anyway...
We're back at karaoke again?
Did you enjoy our little
karaoke date that much?
Player.
Gigolo.
Manwhore.
I did nothing to warrant such slander.
I'll go first, then.
What will you sing?
I liked it when you sang this
the other day, so this is payback.
A BUS WON'T TAKE US TO THE MOON
Wait, this song?
Listen, Arisu! I found this amazing band!
I'm not a special person
Liking the same color
and flavor is one thing,
but can you just happen to like the same
niche band that broke up years ago?
I'm well aware of that
That's why, whenever we talk
Is this some kind of message?
Inohana, are you actually...
I give you the cold shoulder
And now I don't know if that's okay
Huh?
If that's okay
Wha...
And now I'm worried
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Pause!
You all know this band?
Huh? Yep.
We all love them.
We've even played their songs
during lunchtime broadcasts.
But they're such a niche band!
Someone brought an album to school, right?
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Sriram Gurunathan
Mariana Martinez
William Haggard
Wh-Who was it?
Who brought that CD?!
Who knows?
That reminds me!
Apollo could be rather...
Quality Check:
Translation Check:
S Bilyeu
Michelle Tymon
Huh? How'd I learn about this band?
Sorry, I'm kind of...
FORGETFUL